this video is going to tell you at a
该视频将在
high level probably the most important
高水平可能是最重要的
and surprising thing that we have to
和我们必须要做的令人惊讶的事情
tell you about social choice which is
告诉你关于社会选择的
that it's impossible to come up with any
不可能提出任何
social welfare function which is
社会福利功能是
sensible in a particular formal way so
以一种特殊的正式方式明智
first of all let's remember what a
首先，让我们记住
social welfare function is a social
社会福利功能是一种社会
welfare function is a voting rule where
福利功能是一种投票规则
every agent tells me a set of
每个经纪人都告诉我一套
preferences so gives me a total ordering
偏好，所以给了我一个整体的顺序
over all of the choices that we have to
在我们必须要做的所有选择中
make over all of the candidates and
弥补所有候选人
getting this whole set of different
得到这整套不同的
rankings from all of the different
来自所有不同的排名
agents the Social Welfare function gives
代理商的社会福利功能
me back a single ranking which is the
我回到一个单一的排名是
social choice so so think about voting
社会选择，所以考虑投票
over a set of candidates everyone has
每个人都有一套候选人
preferences over all the candidates that
对所有候选人的偏好
we're going to vote over and getting
我们将投票并获得
back a single ranking but that is the
返回单个排名，但这是
kind of aggregate ranking for all the
所有类别的总排名
agents so what would we want such a
代理商，那么我们想要这样一个
ranking to do what would it look like
排名做什么样
for such a ranking to do a good job well
这样的排名才能做好
here's one thing that seems pretty
这是一件看起来很漂亮的东西
obvious that such a ranking function
显然，这种排名功能
should do well say that a ranking for a
应该说一个
social welfare function W is purrito
社会福利函数W是purrito
efficient if any time it's the case that
有效率的话
all of the agents agree on the ordering
所有代理商都同意订购
of two outcomes if everyone thinks that
如果每个人都认为这两个结果
candidate a is better than candidate B
候选人a胜过候选人B
then the social welfare function also
然后社会福利功能
agrees about that part of the ordering
同意订购的那部分
so it might it might say all kinds of
所以它可能会说各种
other things about candidates C D and E
关于候选CD和E的其他内容
but if everybody thinks that a is better
但是如果每个人都认为a更好
than B then the social welfare function
比B那么社会福利功能
also is going to tell us that a is
也要告诉我们a是
better than B it's gonna put a somewhere
比B还好
higher in the ranking than B so and
排名高于B，因此
that's all we're requiring by Pareto
这就是帕累托所需要的
efficiency we're just saying only in the
效率，我们只是在说
case when everybody agrees absolutely
每个人都绝对同意的情况
everybody agrees the social welfare
每个人都同意社会福利
function has to rank in the appropriate
功能必须排在适当的位置
way a second thing we might want is what
我们可能想要的第二件事是
we call independence of irrelevant
我们称无关的独立性
alternatives so we'll say that a social
替代方案，所以我们说
welfare function is independent of
福利功能独立于
irrelevant alternatives
不相关的选择
if the way that I rank between a and B
如果我在A和B之间的排名方式
only depends on the way that all of the
只取决于所有
individual agents ranked a and B so if I
个体代理商排名a和B，所以如果我
want to decide in the social ordering
想决定社会秩序
how it is that that I compare a to B I
我将BI与BI进行比较的方式
should do that only by looking at how
应该只看如何
all of the individual agents relatively
所有个体代理相对
ranked a to B so I shouldn't care about
将A排名为B，所以我不在乎
how everyone felt about a and C or about
每个人对a和C或大概的感觉
B and D I should just look at the a B
B和DI应该只看a B
rankings for everyone and that should
每个人的排名，应该
tell me how the social welfare function
告诉我社会福利的功能
ranks between a and B finally I'll say
最终在a和B之间排名
that a social welfare function has a
社会福利功能具有
dictator if there exists a single agent
独裁者是否存在单个代理
whose preferences we always just return
我们总是会返回谁的偏好
as the social ordering so in other words
换句话说就是社会秩序
if I've got n different agents and they
如果我有n个不同的代理商，他们
always give me some kind of order in and
总是给我某种命令
I just say you know what I only care
我只是说你知道我只在乎
about agent 3 everybody else it just
关于特工3其他所有人
doesn't matter what you tell me I'm
你告诉我我没关系
gonna throw it in the garbage I'm not
要把它扔进垃圾桶，我不是
gonna think about it at all I'm just
我会想一想
gonna give you back agent 3 and I've
会给你特工3，我已经
decided in advance who agent 3 is it's
事先确定谁是代理商3
always gonna be the same guy that's what
永远都是同一个人，这就是
it means for a social welfare function
对社会福利功能意味着
to have a dictator now it's kind of
现在有一个独裁者
terrible for a social welfare function
糟糕的社会福利功能
to have a dictator because it means that
有一个独裁者，因为这意味着
it's not aggregating in any meaningful
它没有聚集在任何有意义的地方
way it's just always reporting back what
只是总是报告什么
one person thanks notice that a social
一个人感谢通知，
welfare function that does have a
福利功能确实具有
dictator trivially satisfies
独裁者平凡地满足
independence of irrelevant alternatives
不相关选择的独立性
and Pareto efficiency because prudhoe
和帕累托效率，因为普拉德霍
efficiency says anytime everybody agrees
效率表示任何人都同意
the social welfare function has to do
社会福利职能必须要做
the right thing and when everybody
正确的事情，当每个人
agrees in particular the dictator also
特别同意独裁者
agreed so so we would get free -
同意，所以我们可以免费-
efficiency for free likewise we would
免费的效率我们同样会
get independence of irrelevant
获得无关的独立性
alternatives for free because we're only
免费的替代品，因为我们只是
gonna care about the dictators a B
要关心独裁者A B
rankings in order to decide the a B
排名以决定A B
ranking and and so we're not looking at
排名，所以我们不在看
anything else from any of the other
其他任何东西
agents so so we see we can satisfy our
代理商，所以我们看到我们可以满足我们的要求
two properties from a dictatorial social
独裁社会的两个属性
welfare function but dictatorial social
福利功能但独裁社会
welfare functions are pretty undesirable
福利功能非常不可取
to us well here's the punchline
对我们来说这是重点
Kenneth arrow in 1951 famously proved
1951年的肯尼斯·阿斯（Kenneth Arrow）著名
the following theorem any social welfare
以下定理任何社会福利
function over three or more outcomes so
作用于三个或更多结果，因此
candidates in elections that have more
选举中候选人更多
than two candidates that is pre to
比两名候选人
efficient and independent of irrelevant
高效且无关紧要
alternatives must be dictatorial so in
替代品必须是独裁的，因此在
other words these these two things that
换句话说，这两件事
that seem very natural that we would
看起来我们很自然
want free to efficiency and independence
想要自由高效和独立
of irrelevant alternatives are so
无关的替代品是这样
constraining on the set of social
约束社会
welfare functions that they imply that
他们暗示的福利功能
we would have to have a dictatorial
我们将不得不独裁
social welfare function since we can't
社会福利功能，因为我们不能
possibly live with a dictatorial social
可能与独裁者生活在一起
welfare function what that really means
福利功能的真正含义
is that we have to give up either pre
是我们必须放弃
doe efficiency or independence of
能源效率或独立性
irrelevant alternatives and that's
无关的选择，那就是
pretty bad news because these are both
坏消息是因为这两个都是
pretty natural things
很自然的东西